<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michael</title>
    <link>https://michaelcoooper.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Michael</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 12:47:50 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://michaelcoooper.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Insight into the Field of Quantum Computing and its Future</title>
      <link>https://michaelcoooper.uk/blog/futureofquantum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 12:47:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelcoooper.uk/blog/futureofquantum/</guid>
      <description>$\newcommand\col[1]{\begin{pmatrix}#1\end{pmatrix}}$
Introduction Classical Computing The classical computer is something we are all familiar with, most, if not all, of us use one every day of our lives. It is well known that a classical computer operates using an expansive array of binary digits, bits, which take discrete values, a 1 or a 0. This is commonly signified by a high or low electrical signal in a computer.
Our classical computers perform operations and store these bits to handle inputs and produce outputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imaging a Black Hole: The Event Horizon Telescope</title>
      <link>https://michaelcoooper.uk/blog/eventhorizontelescope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 23:54:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelcoooper.uk/blog/eventhorizontelescope/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A black hole is a region of the fabric of the universe known as spacetime in which the attractive gravitational force is so strong that nothing, no particles or radiation, is able to escape (1) once it is past its boundary called the event horizon. As no light is able to escape the black hole, previously it has been impossible to visualize what an actual black hole is. As gaseous matter is pulled into a black hole it forms a very large disk due to the rotational motion of the black hole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Blog</title>
      <link>https://michaelcoooper.uk/blog/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 23:06:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelcoooper.uk/blog/first/</guid>
      <description>Introductions Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Michael a first year Computer Science student at the University of Warwick and this is my first attempt at creating a personal website and blog!
A bit about myself first. I am 19 years old and live in a town called Warrington in the beautiful Cheshire countryside. Ideal location for trips to Manchester and Liverpool!
I am also a student at the Univeristy of Warwick. I study Computer Science and have always been interested by computers, how they work and the many amazing things you can do with them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://michaelcoooper.uk/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelcoooper.uk/education/</guid>
      <description>BSc Computer Science @ University of Warwick Oct 2021 - present (expected 2024 graduation) I am currently studying Computer Science at the Univeristy of Warwick.
Actively involved with TEDxWarwick and WarwickAI societies.
    Modules     Programming for Computer Scientists   Mathematics for Computer Scientists 1   Mathematics for Computer Scientists 2   Professional Skills   Design of Information Structures   Computer Organisation and Architecture   Web Development Technologies   Computer Security      A-Levels @ Sir John Deane&amp;rsquo;s Sixth Form College Sep 2019 - Jun 2021 Achieved 3 A*s in Computer Science, Mathematics and Physics with a grade A in AS-Level Further Mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
